Yi-Yang Lin

www.linkedin.com/in/vi-yang-lin

1949 E. University Dr., Apt. 3046, Tempe, AZ 85281

(480)781-6003

Yi-Yang.Lin@asu.edu

Graduate Business Analytics student with two years of experience in supply chain and operation management as well as strong communication skills seeks a position in data science field.

W. P. Carey School of Business at Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

May 2017

Master in Business Analytics, 3.91 GPA

University of Michigan, Coursera

June 2017

Applied Data Science with Python Specialization

John Hopkins University, Coursera

June 2017

Data Science Specialization

National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

June 2012

Bachelor of Business Administration, 3.6 GPA

Module Courses: Operations and Decision-Making Management

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- · Supply Chain Management
- · Data Mining & Machine Learning
- · Data Visualization

- · Negotiation and Communication
- · Cross-Cultural Collaboration
- · Business Intelligence

- · System & Dynamic Simulation
- · Statistical & Decision Modeling, Optimization and Analysis

· SAS Advanced Programmer Certification, Oracle Database SQL Expert, Julia Scientific Programming Certification MongoDB for DBAs Course Completion Confirmation; R, Python, Tableau, Azure ML, Hadoop & AWS, MySQL, NoSQL, SPSS Matlab, Minitab, MS: Word, Access, Project, Advanced Excel: Pivot table & VBA & Palisade

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Associate, W. P. Carey School of Business, Tempe, AZ

October 2016 - Present

Voice and Text Analytics Project, Fire Department, Client Project:

- Using Python compiled with Google API to translate voice to text, and building clustering model to group types of calls.
- Based on the text and sentimental analysis, predicting and giving the priorities of certain events to help schedule dispatchers and to reduce costs.

Machine Learning Platforms Research, Research Project:

- In two platforms groups, used R and Azure ML to do machine learning for classification with 6 different algorithms for thirty data sets and compared with other platforms.
- Helped build the model structure and debugged the codes in the scripts.

Operations Manager, Light Generation Electronics Corp., Taipei, Taiwan

May 2014 - September 2015

- Managed over 10 sales accounts, and the sales of over total ten thousand products.
- Acted as a representative for purchasing process and maintained close relationships with other partners and distributors.
- Developed, amended and oversaw process and procedural documents for every sector in the supply chain which resulted in increased work efficiency.
- Used Excel format and database to manage orders and all required product specifications.
- Participated in developing and upgrading of the company's risk monitoring system which ensured consistency in stock and logistics through statistical analysis of data.

Marketing Manager Associate, Light Generation Electronics Corp., Taipei, Taiwan

October 2013 - May 2014

- Assisted in analyzing merchandise and commodity market, along with global economic and domestic political news to assess investing and marketing strategies.
- Collaborated with the leadership team to determine the price in bulk, leading to 2% profits.
- Communicated with customers and solved technical problems.

Coast Guard for Obligatory Military Service, Coast Guard Administration, Kaohsiung, Taiwan

August 2012 - July 2013

- Patrolled the coast and carefully inspected ships to deter smuggling.
- Provided community services for citizens and fishermen and the inspection office acquired over 90% satisfaction rating.

OTHER PROJECTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Membership of Beta Gamma Sigma, Eligible for Top 20% in Master's Program

April 2017 April 2017

Full Scholarship to INFORMS Conference on Business Analytics & Operations Research 2017, Offered by MSBA Program, W. P. Carey School of Business

March 2017

Second Place in HACK ASU Hackathon / Pitch Competition

Wilson Monitoring: Developed device compiled with data collection by sensors, AWS Machine learning, and web dashboard to monitor and to company the patient.

- Simulated sample data by statistical method, connected the data to AWS, and wrote the Python code for preprocessing.
- Did the data analysis. Based on the result, created slides, built and presented the business model to the judges.

Appointment No Show Prediction and Analysis, Medical Consulting, Capstone Client Project January 2017 - May 2017

- Using R, Python, and Azure ML to do data mining and machine learning to predict the error rate in patient scheduling and to determine appropriate fee for no-shows to reduce costs.
- Developing visualized dashboard to present the analysis and its business value by using Excel and Tableau.

Optimizing Rate of Yeast Fermentation Analysis

October 2016 - December 2016

- Conducted the experiment of yeast with Quality Engineering Method and analyzed the data by Minitab.
- Presented the findings, including data interpretation, conclusion, and future improvements.